# IWUCHUKWU CHIJINDU JOSHUA

Phone: (+230) 5741-7151 <u>iwugodjoshua@gmail.com</u> Candos Vacoas Plaine Wilhemes, Mauritius

# Skype:iwugod3

I have an accumulated average of four years proficient experience in User Interface applications and integration of highly transactional and scalable application, I am a self-thought frontend developer with professional working experience, based in Mauritius. I have learnt that aesthetics and intuitive designs are timeless and great if given proper attention and time. From participating in many projects, seminars and workshops, I have learnt that high coding standards and best practices are critical for both short and long-term success of a project. I attained the following essential attributes; Team work, open communication and compassion that hamper or contribute to productivity. In conclusion, humility, adaptability and curiosity are the essential tools required to stay relevant in the ever-changing world of Information Technology.

# **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

Language/Schema's: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQUERY, AJAX, SASS, AngularJs, ReactJs, Angular

IDE'S: NetBeans, Microsoft Visual Studio, Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text,

Database: MySQL, Mongodb, Firebase, Microsoft SQL Server

Framework: Twitter Bootstrap, AngularJs, ExpressJs, NodeJs, Angular, Umbraco CMS,

ReactJs, MVC.

Version Management: SVN, GIT Web Services: REST

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Frontend Developer - Nosunset Limited - St. Pierre, Mauritius

02/2017 - present

- Primarily working with a team of developers such as backend and software architects to gather requirements, enhance functionality and create new features.
- Create responsive UI's, layout templates from PSD's and implement frontend programming for web applications using HTML, Umbraco CMS, SASS, JQuery, MVC ReactJs, Javascript and Razor according to sprint plan.
- Worked with other team members in UI validations, business logic implementation using various plugins such as slick, fancybox, Angular Js and Adsearch.
- Involved with developing responsive web pages for mobile, tablets and desktop using CSS3 Media queries and fluid grid system.
- Use directives/custom directive to create reusable component across projects.

- Using Backstop Js to test UI and functionality.
- Maintenance of existing and new web sites/ web applications.
- HTML5 emailing Templates.

# Freelance Webmaster/ Frontend Developer – Proximity BBDO – Quatre Bornes 05/2016-12/2016

- Convert PSD to HTML pages, consume backend API calls at the frontend level.
- Responsive and adaptive layout for web pages.
- Test implementations, interact with other team member on improvement in designs and code optimization.
- Web emailing/ Mobile website design and integration.
- Aviation Fuel website for Mobile.
- HTML5 emailing templates

## Freelance Web Developer – I-deal web limited – Ebene

6/2015 - 12/2015

- Manage code base (pull request), Pioneer development, Adhere to standard and practice, Improve convention and documentation, Apply agile system of development and consistently maintain development performance.
- Ongoing design on new and existing web projects
- Liaising closely with the customers or clients to ensure delivery according to client's requirement.
- Design of critical pages and email addresses.
- Interact with project manager, co-developers and clients.
- Enhancing the look and feel of the web pages.
- Fixing bugs encountered during project execution.
- Testing and deployment of website functionality in different browsers to ensure responsive or adapt design on different screen resolution.
- Iteration and modification of project scope according to clients requirement.

#### **EDUCATION**

MS	MSc Enterprise Security and Digital Forensics University of Technology Mauritius	2016
BS	Information Technology and Business Information Systems Middlesex University London	2014
ADSE	Advance Diploma in Software Engineering, ISO9001 Aptech Computer Education	2013

### **Aunsbjerg:**

- Participated in the development of this site, desktop and mobile designs of certain pages such as the checkout page.
- Integration of backend API on frontend level.

Technology: AngularJs, Bootstrap, Umbraco, Razor, Javascript, HTML5, Sass, CSS3, JQuery, GruntJs.

• Link: <a href="https://aunsbjerg.com/">https://aunsbjerg.com/</a>

### Arosv3/ vejlebrandv3:

- Primarily responsible for the development of most products and the checkout pages on this website. The project is for an insurance company in Denmark that sells insurances online.
- Creating pages and responsive templates, writing AngularJs directives to manipulate HTML elements,
- Consume API calls from backend. Test and deploying to Server for onward testing and delivery

Technology: Typescript, Angularjs, Bootstrap, Umbraco CMS, Razor, Javascript, HTML5, Sass, CSS3, JQuery. GruntJs

**Link:** https://minside.veilebrand.dk/beregn-pris

#### **Signit:**

This system is an online signing engine that aims to convert physical documents into digital format such that the converted document is signed via the sender or owner of the document using their online digital identity.

- Started with the maintenance of previous version of the project.
- Built the checkout module (frontend wise)
- Payment module
- Localization of the web site
- Conversion of UI/UX designs to web pages, validating and testing functionalities according to requirement.

Technology: JQuery, AngularJs, Javascript, Umbraco CMS, Razor, HTML5 Sass, Css3, Grunt Link: <a href="https://signit.dk/">https://signit.dk/</a>

### **GreenTechBus:**

- Converted the PSD designs into responsive template using ReactJs plugin to implement the sliding effect of the website.
- Integrate SEO into the system such that an admin can always change SEO tags and it is automatically populated back into the system.
- Worked with other team members in integrating the Multi lingual model for this site using JSON files stored in AWS S3 server.
- Test project using BackstopJs Technology

ReactJs, Sass, AWS S3, HTML5, GIT

• Link: <a href="http://www.greentechbus.com/">http://www.greentechbus.com/</a>

**Links for other projects**: participated in the maintenance, design, and redesign of some component in these system.

https://www.hytor.com/

**HOBBIES:** Soccer, reading, music, dance, swimming

**REFERENCES:** upon requests.